<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>menofgod</title>
<description>menofgod</description>
<link>http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/blog</link>
<item>
<title>
15 Weight Loss Mistakes That Are Halting weight loss
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Been gymming too hard since a month and still can't see any results in your weight? Well, join the league! Because according to a research, there are at least 90 per cent of men who, knowingly or unknowingly, make one of these weight loss mistakes that slow down their weight loss process. Most of us tend to ignore the red signals that are hidden behind these myths. Let's take a look at 15 such mistakes that turn around the weight loss process…in the wrong direction!The All Or Nothing<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/7d69f0531456437d80c89a4ef98d32cf.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>mensxp.com</dc:creator>
<link>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2017/04/26/15-Weight-Loss-Mistakes-That-Are-Halting-weight-loss
</link>
<guid>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2017/04/26/15-Weight-Loss-Mistakes-That-Are-Halting-weight-loss
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/7d69f0531456437d80c89a4ef98d32cf.jpg"/><div>Been gymming too hard since a month and still can't see any results in your weight? Well, join the league! Because according to a research, there are at least 90 per cent of men who, knowingly or unknowingly, make one of these weight loss mistakes that slow down their weight loss process. Most of us tend to ignore the red signals that are hidden behind these myths. Let's take a look at 15 such mistakes that turn around the weight loss process…in the wrong direction!</div><div>The All Or Nothing Approach</div><div>Many of us tend to make strict and ideal diet plans completely ignoring the prospects of possible cravings that occur in us almost every day, especially when you are driving back home after a hectic day at work. There are times when you are too tired of your strict diet that you give into those temptations. Hence, it is important for you to go slow, beginning with an easy to follow diet chart that suits your taste and slowly customizing it to an ideal-for-your-weight-loss diet plan.</div><div>Too Many Limitations</div><div>The more you avoid it, the more you want it. Putting too many restrictions on yourself from eating this or that will not only starve you but also slow down your metabolism . You can't completely cut yourself out from your daily routine diet. So follow your appetite systematically.</div><div>Relying On The Weighing Machine</div><div>Weighing yourself every day, worrying every time the number goes up or stays the same is totally uncalled for. Go easy on yourself, take your sweet time and stop worrying. Weigh yourself only once a week. Worrying too much might cause stress, and stress is known to be your worst enemy when you are trying to lose weight.</div><div>Diet And Exercise Go Hand In Hand </div><div>Exercising regularly and eating high-calorie food at the same time won't do you any good, and neither will following a strict diet while sitting like a couch potato playing video games or watching Ten Sports all day long. Both exercising and dieting have to be combined regularly for positive results.</div><div>Switching To Fat-Free Foods </div><div>While ruling out fatty foods, what most of us don't care about is finding out which fat is good for us, and what's bad for us. After all, not all fats are bad for us. We tend to go for foods with a ‘low fat' or a ‘fat free' label on them, but what we don't realize is that high amounts of sugar (calories) is added to such foods. Hence, it is important for us to watch those labels more closely and eat foods with monosaturated fats, because those aid in weight loss.</div><div>Missing Meals</div><div>Most of us tend to believe that skipping lunch will instantly cut calories and help us lose weight. But what we forget is that our body needs to compensate when you skip a meal. The end result is you skip lunch and you indulge in two samosas in the evening. Pay attention to your increased cravings for your favorite pizza, or Chole Bhature or Tandoori Chicken—you would probably end up gorging during lunch in your office canteen, all because you skipped breakfast!</div><div>No Sundays For Your Diet</div><div>Sundays maybe a day off from work, but you should never turn them into a day off from your diet. You can't just compromise with the hard work you put in following your week long diet by giving in into a chocolate cake on the weekend.</div><div>Easy But Not So Healthy Weight Loss Supplements </div><div>Believe it or not, these supplements offer you everything but natural weight loss. What's worse is that these come packed with the surety of many serious health troubles and side effects, and the weight loss thus caused is at the cost of good health.</div><div>Too Much Healthy Food Intake </div><div>Just because someone told you that fruits are healthy, overeating them will not help your body in any way. Every food contains fat, be it a fruit or a vegetable or meat. Eating healthy as per your diet is important, however eating too much of it can increase your calorie intake leading to increased fats.</div><div>Smoking </div><div>Chances are that most of us cut down on smoking while on a healthy diet for good. However, it is an unavoidable fact that weight gain is a common setback while you are trying to give up smoking. Never let the situation occur where you have to give up smoking, simply by never doing it ever since it slows down your weight losing process.</div><div>Eating Fast </div><div>Eating too fast has tendencies to make you overeat. It is beneficial to eat slow, enjoying every bite of the food peacefully so that your body can hint your brain to halt eating right on time. Also, smaller portions, if not eaten too fast, will make you feel fuller faster and add to your weight loss goals.</div><div>In Love With Salty Snacks </div><div>Salt contains sodium which leads you to eat reflexively. You never realize when you're full and go on munching on salted popcorns throughout the movie or a cricket match. You may give up on such a habit with ease since it is easily possible to reduce your salt cravings in just a few weeks of a low-salt diet.</div><div>Alcohol </div><div>“Give up on beer? No!” might be your thoughts just as now. However, you may try quitting for a week and see if you can live on less. Low-carb beer and reducing the number of pints can be an alternative for you.</div><div>Dozing Off Right After Meals </div><div>It is common knowledge that you must take a walk after meals to facilitate digestion. The longer the food stays in your small intestine, the longer it takes to digest, furthermore increasing absorption of fats in your body.</div><div>Following The Same Old Diet Plan Forever</div><div>You need to customize your diet chart as per the amount of weight you're losing every week. Along with your weight loss, your calorie needs to keep on changing and should to be adjusted on time.</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>14 Vegetarian Foods That Have More Iron Than Meat</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Whether you’re a lifelong vegetarian or are actively transitioning to a non-meat diet, a common concern is making sure you still consume plenty of iron. According to the National Institutes of Health, the recommended dietary allowances (RDAs) of iron for adults is 8-27 mg per day, with adult men tending toward the lower end, while older women and those who are pregnant or breastfeeding need more.While meat is often at the top of the list of recommended sources of iron, there are plenty of<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/180ba81999a64ad3aa42735d409ecab6.jpg/v1/fill/w_455%2Ch_302/180ba81999a64ad3aa42735d409ecab6.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>ELANA HOPMAN FOR RODALE’S ORGANIC LIFE</dc:creator>
<link>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2017/04/21/14-Vegetarian-Foods-That-Have-More-Iron-Than-Meat
</link>
<guid>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2017/04/21/14-Vegetarian-Foods-That-Have-More-Iron-Than-Meat
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 10:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/180ba81999a64ad3aa42735d409ecab6.jpg"/><div>Whether you’re a lifelong vegetarian or are actively transitioning to a non-meat diet, a common concern is making sure you still consume plenty of iron. According to the National Institutes of Health, the recommended dietary allowances (RDAs) of iron for adults is 8-27 mg per day, with adult men tending toward the lower end, while older women and those who are pregnant or breastfeeding need more.</div><div>While meat is often at the top of the list of recommended sources of iron, there are plenty of non-meat options that contain the same amount of iron, or more, than meat. So no need to give up on your vegetarian diet and reach for a burger (or a multivitamin)—these 14 foods will easily boost your iron intake.</div><div>SPINACH</div><div>Dark leafy greens, especially spinach, provide a powerhouse of iron. Three cups of spinach contain about 18 mg of iron—that's more than an 8-ounce steak! You can meet your daily RDA of iron with just one hearty spinach salad. </div><div>BROCCOLI</div><div>Not only is broccoli jam-packed with iron and other key nutrients like vitamin K and magnesium, it’s also high in vitamin C, which helps encourage iron absorption in the body. (And you may be surprised to learn that it's quite good in smoothies.)</div><div>LENTILS</div><div>Just one cup of lentils has more iron than an 8-ounce steak. Lentils are also a solid source for dietary fiber, potassium, and protein. You can add lentils to your salad, or try soup—make it in bulk, then freeze the leftovers for later. </div><div>KALE</div><div>Three cups of kale contain 3.6 mg of iron. Try this kale salad or this kale and lemon pizza.</div><div>BOK CHOY</div><div>Whether you steam or sauté this tasty Chinese cabbage, you’ll be getting a healthy dose of vitamin A, in addition to 1.8 mg of iron per cup. </div><div>BAKED POTATO</div><div>One large baked potato contains nearly three times the amount of iron as a 3-ounce serving of chicken. Top it with Greek yogurt (a high-protein substitute for sour cream), steamed broccoli, and a bit of melted cheese for a tasty weeknight dinner.</div><div>SESAME SEEDS</div><div>Just one tablespoon of sesame seeds contains 1.3 mg of iron. And it's super simple to incorporate them into your diet, too. Sprinkle sesame seeds over a salad for added flavor and crunch or mix them into a dressing, sauce, or salsa before pouring over a dish. </div><div>CASHEWS</div><div>Nuts of all kinds are a well-known protein sources for vegetarians, but cashews have the added benefit of being very rich in iron. One ¼-cup serving contains about 2 grams of iron. Not a fan of their nutty texture? Hide them in a smoothie to get the health benefits without the grit.</div><div>SOYBEANS</div><div>A single cup of cooked soybeans contains between 8 and 9 mg of iron. These legumes are a great source of protein, too (they're one of the 20 highest protein vegetarian foods). Just be sure to seek out organic soy products rather than conventional, which may be genetically modified.</div><div>CHICKPEAS</div><div>One cup of chickpeas contains 4.7 mg of iron, more than half the daily RDA for an adult male. Roast them in a bit of olive oil for a crunchy snack, or mix them with tomatoes, feta, and cucumber to create a savory side dish.</div><div>DARK CHOCOLATE</div><div>The benefits of dark chocolate seem endless. In addition to promoting healthier skin and teeth and reducing anxiety, dark chocolate also offers a sweet way to up your iron intake. One ounce of dark chocolate contains 2 to 3 mg of iron, more iron than in the same amount of beef.</div><div>SWISS CHARD</div><div>Just one cup of Swiss chard has 4 mg of iron, more than a 6-ounce hamburger. Swiss chard also contains valuable nutrients, including omega-3 fatty acids, vitamins A, C, and K, and B folates.</div><div>TOFU</div><div>A vegetarian staple for years, firm tofu boasts 3 mg of iron per half cup. There are countless recipes for using tofu, from a simple stir-fry to a sweet, homemade peach sorbet. </div><div>KIDNEY BEANS</div><div>Kidney beans contain 3-4 mg of iron per cup. Be sure to cook kidney beans to get the best flavor and texture. Kidney beans are the superstars of vegetarian chili, often acting as a hearty base ingredient in favor of meat options. Consider purchasing dried beans in bulk for a budget-friendly option. </div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Healthy Foods That Calm & De-Stress</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
1. Asparagus is a power food that is full of B vitamins that help to calm and de-stress you. They taste great steamed but can also be lightly seasoned, thrown raw into salads or they go great in stir-fries.They're also tasty broiled and seasoned.It's true that side effects may include off-color or funky-smelling urine. But it's a small price to pay for all the folate they deliver. The B vitamin is essential in helping you keep your cool when stress rears its ugly head. 2. Avocados are an<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/f907b7_920f6df5b2564360adabdc196bf22b3a.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Various sources</dc:creator>
<link>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2015/05/10/10-Healthy-Foods-That-Calm-DeStress
</link>
<guid>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2015/05/10/10-Healthy-Foods-That-Calm-DeStress
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 08:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>1. Asparagus is a power food that is full of B vitamins that help to calm and de-stress you. They taste great steamed but can also be lightly seasoned, thrown raw into salads or they go great in stir-fries.They're also tasty broiled and seasoned.</div><div>It's true that side effects may include off-color or funky-smelling urine. But it's a small price to pay for all the folate they deliver. The B vitamin is essential in helping you keep your cool when stress rears its ugly head. </div><div>2. Avocados are an excellent sourceof healthy fats, these creamy green fruits (yes, fruits) can help you block stress. They're rich in glutathione, a substance that blocks intestinal absorption of certain fats that cause oxidative damage (the process that creates free radicals, the harmful compounds responsible for aging). Avocados also contain more folate than any other fruit. Try to stick to a single serving (about one- quarter of an avocado). Thinly sliced, it can go a long way on salads or replace mayo on sandwiches or burgers.</div><div>3. BERRIES</div><div>All berries, including blueberries, strawberries, raspberries, and blackberries, are rich in vitamin C, which has been shown to be helpful in combating stress. German researchers tested this by asking 120 people to give a speech and then do hard math problems. Those who had been given vitamin C had lower blood pressure and lower levels of cortisol after the stressfest. Add a handful of berries to salad, yogurt, or oatmeal, or try nibbling on them frozen.</div><div>3. Oranges and other citrus fruits are vitamin C powerhouses. What's even better about them is that they can be taken on the go. You can just throw them in your pocket, backpack or purse and forget about them until you're ready for an easy, inexpensive snack. Try some other varieties, like clementines, tangelos, or mineolas.</div><div>4. Research has proven that these shelled marvels provide more than one kind of cognitive edge. Walnuts contain alpha- linolenic acid, an essential omega-3 fatty acid, and other polyphenols that have been shown to help prevent memory loss. And studies conducted by the National Institutes of Health found that the omega-3 fatty acids in walnuts keep the stress hormones cortisol and adrenaline in check. To bring out their flavor, try toasting them for 10 minutes, then chop them and add them to salads. They can also be ground up and substituted for flour. </div><div>5. Tea is a no-brainer. While there is some caffeine in certain types of tea, both black and green varieties can help you relax. Green tea contains an amino acid called theanine, which has been linked to reducing anxiety and promoting sleep. And a 2006 study found that black tea drinkers were both quicker to de-stress and less stressed in general than people given a tea substitute, WebMD reported.</div><div>6. Oatmeal provides a great healthy and filling carb. Carbs naturally boost your mood by kick-starting serotonin production in the brain. Grains with more fiber take longer to digest, though, thereby releasing serotonin at a more slow-and-steady pace.</div><div>7. Leafy Greens are full of magnesium. Magnesium is a mineral crucial to a smoothly running body. It helps muscles relax and also calms the nerves. It's found naturally in green veggies, particularly leafy ones, like kale and spinach.</div><div>8. You probably thought you'd read about oysters in the Sexy Foods section, huh? They earned a place here because they're a mother lode of zinc. Six oysters—what you'd typically be served in a restaurant as an appetizer—have more than half the recommended daily allowance for this important calming mineral. They're an acquired taste, for sure, but fans love 'em with cocktail sauce, horseradish, or mignonette. Purists favor a simple squeeze of lemon.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/f907b7_920f6df5b2564360adabdc196bf22b3a.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Eat Well on a Budget</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
When you've got a tight budget, meal planning and grocery shopping has its challenges. And, when you have a tight budget and you're dedicated to eating healthy, it's even trickier.Here are some smart tips from our readers that make eating healthy on a tight budget feel easy!1. Buy fresh produce when it's in season and freeze it.Fresh produce is always great, but the cost can add up fast. Stick with buying what's currently in season, and consider stocking up when you find a good deal.Local<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/f907b7_a9b8ef532abd4058ab4e2c5a95987e54.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Kelli Foster &amp; Adda Bjarnadottir</dc:creator>
<link>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2015/07/01/How-to-Eat-Well-on-a-Budget-1
</link>
<guid>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2015/07/01/How-to-Eat-Well-on-a-Budget-1
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>When you've got a tight budget, meal planning and grocery shopping has its challenges. And, when you have a tight budget and you're dedicated to eating healthy, it's even trickier.</div><div>Here are some smart tips from our readers that make eating healthy on a tight budget feel easy!</div><div>1. Buy fresh produce when it's in season and freeze it.</div><div>Fresh produce is always great, but the cost can add up fast. Stick with buying what's currently in season, and consider stocking up when you find a good deal.</div><div>Local produce that is in season is generally cheaper. It is also usually at its peak in both nutrients and flavor.</div><div>Produce that is not in season has often been transported halfway around the world to get to your store, which is not good for either the environment or your budget.</div><div>Also, buy produce by the bag if you can. That is usually a lot cheaper than buying by the piece.</div><div>If you buy more than you need, you can freeze the rest or incorporate it into next week’s meal plans.</div><div>2. Look for sales and plan meals accordingly.</div><div>If your local grocery store offers a savings card be sure to sign up, and check the weekly circular to see what's on sale. Instead of shopping for groceries based on your weekly meal plan, consider planning your meals around what's on sale.</div><div>If you have favorite products or staples that you use frequently, you should stock up on them when they’re on sale.</div><div>If you’re sure that it’s something you’ll definitely use, you may as well stock up and save a little money.</div><div>Just make sure that it will last for a while and won’t expire in the meantime. It will not save you any money to buy something you’ll end up throwing out later on.</div><div>3. Try less expensive cuts of meat.</div><div>You can still enjoy meat, even when you're on a tight budget. Look for less expensive cuts of meat, like chicken thighs instead of chicken breasts, and try different cooking methods, like the slow cooker, to make tougher cuts of meat tender and juicy.</div><div>These are great to use in burritos, casseroles, soups, stews and stir fries.</div><div>It may also be helpful to buy a large and inexpensive cut of meat to use in several different meals during the week.</div><div>4. Replace Meat with Other Proteins</div><div>Eating less meat may be a good way to save money.</div><div>Try having one or two days per week where you use other protein sources, such as legumes, hemp seeds, eggs or canned fish.</div><div>These are all very inexpensive, nutritious and easy to prepare. Most of them also have a long shelf life and are therefore less likely to spoil quickly.</div><div>5. Embrace whole grains and beans.</div><div>Beans and whole grains, like quinoa, freekeh and brown rice are an inexpensive and tasty way to bulk up meals, and can even be a meal in themselves.</div><div>Some foods are way cheaper in less processed form.</div><div>For example, a block of cheese is cheaper than shredded cheese and canned beans are cheaper than refried ones.</div><div>Whole grains, like brown rice and oats, are also cheaper per serving than most processed cereals.</div><div>The less processed foods are also often sold in larger quantities, and yield more servings per package.</div><div>6. Plan and prep meals ahead.</div><div>When it comes to saving money at the grocery store, planning is essential. </div><div>Use one day each week to plan your meals for the upcoming week. Then, make a grocery list of what you need.</div><div>Whether it's veggies for the week, tomorrow's breakfast, lunches or dinners, prepping food in advance is a step in the right direction towards eating healthy. Plus, it's also a good way to make sure you're eating what's in the fridge, to minimize waste.</div><div>Also, make sure to scan your fridge and cabinets to see what you already have. There are usually a lot of foods hidden in the back that can be used.</div><div>Only plan to purchase what you know you’re going to use, so that you don’t end up throwing away a lot of what you buy.</div><div>7. Cook at Home</div><div>Cooking at home is much cheaper than eating out.</div><div>Make it a habit to cook at home, rather than eating out at the last minute.</div><div>Generally, you can feed an entire family of 4 for the same price as buying food for one or two people at a restaurant.</div><div>Some people find it best to cook for the entire week on the weekends, while others cook one meal at a time.</div><div>By cooking yourself, you also gain the benefit of knowing exactly what is in your food.</div><div>8. Pack Your Lunch</div><div>Eating out is very expensive, especially if done regularly.</div><div>Packing your lunch, snacks, drinks and other meals is less expensive and way healthier than eating out.</div><div>If you have adapted to cooking large meals at home, you’ll always have a steady lunch to bring with you without any additional effort or cost.</div><div>It does require some planning, but it should save you a lot of money at the end of the month.</div><div>9. Broaden your culinary horizons!</div><div>Cuisines, like Mexican and Indian, rely heavily on inexpensive ingredients, like beans and rice.</div><div>There are a lot of foods available that are both inexpensive and healthy.</div><div>By making some adjustments and using ingredients that you may not be used to, you can prepare many delicious and inexpensive meals.</div><div>Try increasing your use of eggs, beans, seeds, frozen fruits and vegetables, cheaper cuts of meat and whole grains.</div><div>These all taste great, are cheap (especially in bulk) and very nutritious.</div><div>10. Stop Buying Junk Food</div><div>Cut out some of the junk food from your diet.</div><div>You would be surprised to see how much you may be paying for soda, crackers, cookies, prepackaged meals and processed foods.</div><div>Despite the fact that they offer very little nutrition and are packed with unhealthy ingredients, they are also very expensive.</div><div>By skipping the processed and unhealthy foods, you can spend more of your budget on higher quality, healthy foods.</div><div>11. Keep an organized fridge and pantry.</div><div>Leftovers are always great, but it totally defeats the purpose if they get lost in the back of the fridge. Label leftovers and keep your fridge organized to help minimize food waste.</div><div>12. Repurpose leftovers.</div><div>If you don't like eating the same meal over and over, consider repurposing leftovers into an entirely new and delicious meal.</div><div>Cooking large meals can save you both time and money.</div><div>Leftovers can be used for lunches, in other recipes or frozen in single-portion sizes to be enjoyed later on.</div><div>Leftovers usually make very good stews, stir-fries, salads and burritos. These types of food are especially great for people on a budget</div><div>13. Go to the farmers market at the end of the day.</div><div>Depending on where you live, farmers markets may or may not save you money during regular hours. Consider visiting the market at the end of the day, when you could very likely score some great deals.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/f907b7_a9b8ef532abd4058ab4e2c5a95987e54.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
7 Vegetarian-Friendly Complete Proteins That Aren’t Tofu
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
If you're living the meat-free life, you've probably assured concerned family and friends at least once that you do indeed get plenty of protein in your diet. "There is often a myth that vegetarians won't get adequate protein," says Vandana Sheth, R.D.N., C.D.E. "Really, it's very easy to meet your protein needs on a vegetarian diet."That's not to say it doesn't take a little planning. The key to going veggie the smart way is to make sure you're getting plenty of complete proteins in your<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/dd445b_b6e2126be82742f3be7734c09090998a%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Womens Health</dc:creator>
<link>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2016/07/15/7-Vegetarian-Friendly-Complete-Proteins-That-Aren%E2%80%99t-Tofu
</link>
<guid>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2016/07/15/7-Vegetarian-Friendly-Complete-Proteins-That-Aren%E2%80%99t-Tofu
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/dd445b_b6e2126be82742f3be7734c09090998a~mv2.jpg"/><div>If you're living the meat-free life, you've probably assured concerned family and friends at least once that you do indeed get plenty of protein in your diet. &quot;There is often a myth that vegetarians won't get adequate protein,&quot; says Vandana Sheth, R.D.N., C.D.E. &quot;Really, it's very easy to meet your protein needs on a vegetarian diet.&quot;</div><div>That's not to say it doesn't take a little planning. The key to going veggie the smart way is to make sure you're getting plenty of complete proteins in your diet—which provide the nine essential amino acids that your body needs to function, but can't produce on its own. Most complete proteins come from foods like meat, poultry, fish, eggs, dairy products, and soy. But what if you've tried every tofu stir-fry recipe under the sun—and you're getting a little sick of the slimy squares? </div><div>Luckily, there are certain combinations of vegetarian-friendly eats—like legumes, nuts, grains, seeds and protein-rich veggies—that form a complete protein when consumed off the same plate. Here are seven options that will satisfy your needs—no tofu in sight.</div><div>PEANUT BUTTER SANDWICH</div><div>Transform this go-to childhood lunch into your grown-up breakfast of choice. It packs some real nutritional value, Sheth says. &quot;Make sure your breakfast starts out with some kind of protein,&quot; says Sheth. She recommends spreading any variety of nut butter onto a piece of whole-grain toast to start your morning on the right foot—two tablespoons of PB on bread packs 11 grams of protein. Who needs scrambled eggs?</div><div>RICE AND BEANS</div><div>As if you needed another reason to dig into a burrito bowl, this classic coupling comes together to form a complete protein with nine grams in just one cup of equal parts black beans and rice. Go ahead and spoon on some guac for an additional boost of healthy monounsaturated fats.</div><div>HUMMUS AND PITA</div><div>The Mediterranean diet has a super healthy reputation for a reason. When combined with a good-for-you grain, chickpea-packed hummus provides a tasty protein-rich snack. The delicious dip contains three grams of protein per one-quarter cup. Plus, if you opt for whole-grain pita bread, you'll stay full and curb those mid-morning cravings, too. &quot;Any grain is going to give you the amino acids, but I would be pushing for the whole-grain or multigrain, so you get some of the fiber and other nutrients as well,&quot; says Sheth. </div><div>SPINACH SALAD</div><div>If salads are your favorite lunch staple, toss some greens into your bowl along with nuts, beans, or seeds for a great crunch and a meal that delivers a killer complete protein combo. &quot;Spinach is one of those high-protein vegetables,&quot; says Sheth. The dark, leafy green contains a gram of protein per cup, according to the USDA. She recommends using spinach as your base and drizzling some olive oil on top.</div><div>LENTIL SOUP AND BREAD</div><div>A hearty bowl of lentil soup might be tasty, but it won't do the trick on its own. &quot;When you talk about legumes such as lentils, beans, and peas, they usually lack two of the amino acids,&quot; says Sheth. She recommends pairing your delectable dish with a slice of whole-wheat bread for extra fiber, and a full dose of the essential amino acids you need. </div><div>BEAN BURRITO</div><div>There’s a reason why classic favorites like the bean burrito withstand the test of time—they’ve got major nutritional potential. Fill a flour tortilla with black beans and veggies, and you won't even miss the meat, says Sheth. Burritos not your thing? No sweat! You'll get the same complete protein combo with any grain and bean dish. Think: bean tacos, nachos, or enchiladas. Margarita, optional!</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Recipe: Mushroom and Chickpea Stew</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
To create your second blog post, click here to open the Blog Manager. Edit your Published Post entitled 'This is the title of your second post’, add your own text, images or videos, and click ‘Publish'! From the Blog Manager you can also add a brand new post in a breeze. Adding fun and compelling videos is a great way to engage your audience and keep them coming back for more. Also, don’t forget to use relevant keywords in your text for SEO purposes.<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/f907b7_46b8455c69db4a3793a516d63baece89.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<link>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2015/06/10/Recipe-Mushroom-and-Chickpea-Stew
</link>
<guid>
http://menofgod.wixsite.com/nutritales/single-post/2015/06/10/Recipe-Mushroom-and-Chickpea-Stew
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 08:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>To create your second blog post, click here to open the Blog Manager. Edit your Published Post entitled 'This is the title of your second post’, add your own text, images or videos, and click ‘Publish'! From the Blog Manager you can also add a brand new post in a breeze.</div><div>Adding fun and compelling videos is a great way to engage your audience and keep them coming back for more. Also, don’t forget to use relevant keywords in your text for SEO purposes.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/f907b7_46b8455c69db4a3793a516d63baece89.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>